Quiahn M Ballou

■ quiahnb@gmail.com | □ 5189614809 | ♥ Cohoes, NY | ♦ https://quiahn.github.io/Quiahn/

Summary ______

Motivated, detail-oriented web developer with a background in IT and Networking. Experienced in fullstack web development.

Skills _____

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Express, JQuery, Node JS, Mongoose, Django, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS

Tools: MongoDB, Microsoft Azure, Git

Experience _____

Software Engineer Immersive

Boston, MA

June 2021 - September 2021

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

- Designed and built 5 secure full-stack web applications.
 - Modeled and stored data in SQL and NoSQL databases.
 - Consumed and integrated third-party APIs in applications.
 - Built front-ends & back-ends using latest technologies.
 - Deployed applications to the web using cloud-based hosting.
 - Worked in an agile scrum format to develop a working product as a member of a team.

Seasonal TA Clifton Park, NY WALMART October 2018 - June 2021

· Arrange properties, furniture, merchandise, backdrops, or other accessories, as shown in prepared sketches.

• Maintain cleanliness of area and product arrangement.

Projects _____

File Storage Project - Archi.vin

ARCHI.VIN IS A AUDIO FILE SHARING SERVICE WHERE YOU CAN UPLOAD SONGS AND SHARE IT WITH JUST A URL.

To Do List Project - Monthly

MONTHLY IS A OPEN SOURCE WEB APP USED TO TRACK MONTHLY GOALS AND ASPIRATIONS THAT YOU SET.

Hackathon Project - CardWars

CARDWARS IS A CARD GAME BASED ON THE CARD GAME WAR. THIS WAS A HACKATHON PROJECT FOR MINTBEAN'S HIRING HACKATHON FOR JR WEB DEVELOPERS.

Social Media Project - Your Turn

YOUR TURN IS A EXPERIMENTAL SOCIAL MEDIA THAT ALLOWS USERS TO DRAW A NUMBER AND POST FOR A CHANCE AT GETTING THEIR POST SHOWN ON THE HOME PAGE.

React, Express, CosmosDB, Bootstrap, SASS, Microsoft Azure https://github.com/Quiahn/archi.vin

React, Express, MongoDB, Bootstrap, SASS https://github.com/NIQ-Project/nig

React, Express, MongoDB, Tailwind

https://github.com/Quiahn/Mintbeanhackathon-project

> JQuery, Express, MongoDB, Bootstrap, SASS

https://github.com/Quiahn/your-turn

Education

General Assembly CERTIFICATION IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE REMOTE

Boston, MA

June 2021 - September 2021

Albany, NY

Capital Region Career and Technical School CERTIFICATION IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY/NETWORKING

September 2016 - June 2018